Those Who Dance in the Shadows
《水月：このチャクラ…　何だ？》
What is this chakra?
《大蛇丸：ここにいる全員→
They all sense the chakra,
感知タイプじゃないにもかかわらず
チャクラを感じている。
even though none of them
are sensory types.
このチャクラは…》
This chakra is...
（サスケ）行くぞ。
さっさと案内しろ　大蛇丸。
Let's go.
Hurry and
lead the way, Orochimaru.
《少し気になっているようね
ナルト君が》
It looks like he's a bit concerned...
about Naruto.
（シー）これは九尾の…
いや　ナルトのチャクラか？
That's Nine Tails'—
I mean, Naruto's chakra!
（九喇嘛）うまく　わしのチャクラを
変化させ　渡せたな　ナルト。
Nice work transforming and
transferring my chakra, Naruto!
（ナルト）コツはわかった。
一緒に頼むぜ　九喇嘛。
I've gotten the hang of it.
Work with me, Kurama!
《奈良の忍め。
That shinobi Nara,
わしのチャクラ受け渡しに関して
よく分析してやがったな》
he sure analyzed my chakra
exchange capabilities extensively.
ずいぶん待たせちまったからな。
We've kept them waiting a while.
影分身も少しなら大丈夫だ。
A few shadow clones should be okay.
おう！
Got it!
《ヒナタ：す　すごい…
こんなチャクラをナルト君は》
A-Amazing... Naruto is able
to use this chakra...
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
（シカマル）遅えぞ　ナルト！
わりい。
You're late, Naruto!
Sorry!
チョウジ　いの！
（いの）う　うん！
Choji! Ino!
O-Okay!
（チョウジ）何これ　カロリーが。
What...is this?
Are these calories?
（キバ）おい　チョウジ！また太ってんぞ。
Hey! Choji!
You're gaining weight again!
That brat Naruto... Is he giving
them the Nine Tails' chakra?
（マダラ）ナルトのガキ。
九尾のチャクラを渡してるのか。
（オビト）フン。
《八卦空掌！》
8 Trigrams Air Palm!
《力が…　湧いてくる》
I feel...my power surging!
（ヒアシ）ただの空掌であれを。
She did that with just an Air Palm?!
小娘が。　ナルトの力を受けて
ずいぶんと強くなったな。
That girl...
She's gotten quite strong after
getting power from Naruto...
（チョウジたち）倍化の術！
Expansion Jutsu!
シカマル！　いの！　準備オーケー！？
Shikamaru! Ino!
Are you ready?!
おう。
うん！
- Yeah!
- Okay!
《シカク：みんな　作戦はわかったな。
You all understand the plan, right?
Beat it into your heads!
各自頭に叩き込んでおけ。
まずは猪鹿蝶だ》
Start with Ino-Shika-Cho!
《もし　その作戦が
うまくいかなかったら？》
What if the plan doesn't work?
《生きて　てめえが指揮をとれ
シカマル》
Then you live on and
take the reins, Shikamaru.
《いのいち：本部は
これから消える》
HQ will be wiped out shortly.
《フッ　親父として
面と向き合ってやれたのは→
The only face time I spent with you
as your father
was when we played shogi.
暇つぶしの将棋くらいだったな。
お前には何も…》
《シカマル：十分だ》
I haven't given you a thing--
You gave me plenty.
ん？
《親父の背中見て　育ったからよ》
I was able to grow up,
staring at your back, Dad.
フン。
《いの…。
Ino...
お前は　山中家の紫の家紋→
You've grown up to become
the embodiment
萩の花言葉どおりに
育ってくれた》
of the Yamanaka clan's purple crest,
the bush clover, and what it symbolizes...
《いの：前向きな恋　でしょ》
Optimistic love...right?
《いのいち：萩の花言葉は
それだけじゃない。
That's not the only thing
the bush clover stands for.
父さんが何より誇りに思うのは→
The thing I am most proud of
is your care and compassion...
お前の友に対する思いだ》
for your friends!
《いのいち：お前は
きれいな萩の花を→
I've watched you blossom into
a beautiful bush clover flower...
咲かせて見せてくれた》
《さて　そろそろ時間だ。
Our time's almost up.
最後に言い残したいことは
あるか？　シカク》
Do you have any final words, Shikaku?
《ん～　母ちゃんに
伝えといてくれるか　シカマル。
Hmm...
Could you tell your mom
this for me, Shikamaru...
あっ　その前に　母ちゃんに
見つからねえように→
Wait! Before that, throw out
that thing in the wooden box
on the left-hand shelf
of the storeroom
物置の左棚の木箱の中の…》
without your mom finding out!
《全部わかってるよ　心配すんな》
I know all about it...
Don't worry...
《ハハ…》
《最後に俺からだ。
Lastly, from me...
俺たちは
いつもお前たちのなかにいる》
Never forget that we live on
inside of you forever.
《忘れんなよ》
Don't forget!
なめるな！
Don't mock me!
なに！？
影真似の…。
心転身の…。
What?!
- Shadow Possession...
- Mind Transfer...
（２人）術！
- Jutsu!
《いの：入った》
《チッ　またか》
I'm in!
Tsk... They did it again!
うわっ…　この！
Damn you!
俺よりはやく。
They're faster than me!
ナイスだ　いの。
Nice, Ino!
クッ。
次々くるな。
今度は　奈良のしばりの術。
They just keep on coming...
Now it's the Nara's Paralysis jutsu...
（みんな）奈良一族をなめるな。
- Don't mess with the Nara Clan!
よし　動きは止めた。
All right! We stopped him
in his tracks!
もういいぞ　いの！
You can stop now, Ino!
うっ。
大丈夫か？
Are you all right?!
う　うん。
Y-Yeah...
クッ。
（リー）ネジ！
Neji!
（ガイ）リー　もう泣くな。
Lee, stop crying!
（テンテン）リー。
Lee...
（ガイ）リーよ　我らが
ネジの思いを捨てぬかぎり→
Lee...
So long as we don't abandon
Neji's convictions,
ネジは　我々の中でつながり
生きている。
he will continue to live on,
connected inside all of us.
（オビト）お前らに
いいことを教えてやる。
Let me share a little something
with you.
そのつながりが
今の俺を作ったのだ。
It's those connections that
made me what I am today!
それは　強い呪いでもあることを
知っておけ。
You ought to know that bonds
can be powerful curses too!
（カカシ）ナルト　俺が言ったんだよな
お前に。
Naruto...
I was the one who once told you,
仲間は　絶対　殺させやしないと。
"I will never let my comrades die..."
あれはな　俺自身に言い聞かせた
戒めでもあるんだ。
Those words are also
an admonition aimed at myself.
俺は　今まで
多くの仲間を守れなかった。
I haven't been able to save
many comrades.
（カカシ）だから　今度こそ
守ると口にする。
Which is why I keep telling
myself this time, I will protect them.
だが　そのたびに
仲間を守れなかった事実を→
But then, I end up having to face
the fact that I couldn't once more.
見つめ直すことになる。
その傷と一生
向き合っていくことになるんだ。
I'll be confronting those wounds...
for the rest of my life.
だから　忍び耐える者→
But that's why we're ninja.
忍者なんだろ　俺たちは。
We are those who endure.
忘れさせてなんてくれねえよ。
They'll never let you forget.
そもそも　その傷が→
But it's those wounds that prove
your comrades live on inside here.
仲間がここで生きてる
ってことじゃねえのかよ。
Your friends are still alive
in here...
夢の中で　自分が傷つかねえように
作った仲間なんて→
Friends that you create
inside a dream,
so you can't get hurt,
aren't real.
本物じゃねえ。
それって
本物の仲間を消すってことだ。
That means you're just erasing
your real friends!
呪いだろうが　何だろうが→
Curse or not, I want to keep
the real Neji right here.
俺は　本当のネジを
ここに置いておきてえ。
《本当のネジを…　ここに》
The real Neji...right here...
((とあぁ！
（ネジ）柔拳！
Gentle Fist!
無駄だ　リー。　努力したところで
お前に俺は倒せない。
It's no use, Lee.
No matter how hard you try,
you'll never defeat me.
(これは決まっていることだ
ライバルなら他を当たれ))
That's just how things are.
Look for a different rival.
((俺の負け試合　見ていたのか。
So you saw me lose.
なぁ　リー。　俺は今まで→
Hey, Lee, I used to think that
you couldn't change the fate
that was handed to you...
決められた運命は
変えられないと思っていた。
リー　いつかお前の剛拳と俺の柔拳→
One day, I'll fight you for real,
so we can see which is greater,
どちらの拳が上か
本気で戦ってやる。
your Ferocious Fist
or my Gentle Fist.
(ただし　俺の目の黒いうちは
負けはしない))
But...I shall not lose so long
as my eyes are black.
((テンテン：それを言うなら
目の白いうちじゃないの？
In your case, Neji, isn't it
the white of your eyes?
ネジの場合。
（ネジ）あぁ…　うん。
Oh... Yeah... But anyway...
You have me as your rival.
(まぁとにかく
ライバルとして俺がいるってことだ))
《カカシ：前回よりも
はるかに強く…　多い》
It's a lot stronger than before,
and more of it than last time.
((シカク：さっき聞いた一連の情報で
確かめたいことがある。
There's something I want to confirm
regarding the intel from
the last battle sequence...
カカシ　お前は神威で時空間を
行き来したうえ→
Kakashi, you said that
the reason why
you were able to travel
through space time using Kamui,
八尾まで
ほぼ出し入れできたのは→
plus pull Eight Tails
in and out almost whole,
九尾のチャクラを　ナルトから
もらったおかげだと言ったな。
was thanks to receiving
Nine Tails' chakra from Naruto, right?
（カカシ）はい。
Yes ...
正確に言えば　九尾に直接
チャクラをもらいました。
To be more precise,
I received that chakra
directly from Nine Tails...
お前の　「できたのは」という
言い回しから見て→
In reference to your choice
of words, "Thanks to..."
九尾のチャクラなしでの神威は→
How different was it
compared to using Kamui
without Nine Tails' chakra?
ありのときと
どれほど違うと感じた？
簡単でいい　説明してくれ。
Explain it to me in simple terms.
おそらく　３倍以上です。
I would say more than
three times the power.
それまで
神威で飛ばせる回数も大きさも→
I couldn't really hurl things
that were very large
(たいしたことは
なかったですから))
or do it very often before that.
ほぼ渡し終えたか…。
Almost done?
フンッ　貴様の思いどおりになったな。
Humph... Looks like things
have gone your way, Fourth Hokage!
四代目　火影…。
今　わしのチャクラとリンクできるのは→
NARUTO     NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
Until now, the only one who was
able to link their chakra to mine
クシナの血を引き人柱力として→
NARUTO     NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
was Naruto because
he possesses Kushina's
長年　付き添うことになった→
NARUTO     NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
and because he has been
my Jinchuriki for many years...
ナルトだけだ。
そして　ナルトはわしのチャクラを→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA
And Naruto has matured
to the point
ほかの忍共一人ひとりに→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA
where he's skillful enough to sense
and transmute my chakra
合うように感知し　変化させ→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA
to be compatible with other shinobi
and then hand it over to them.
渡すことができるほど→
器用に成長した。
まぁ　わし自身も　ナルトを介せば→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA  NINJA
Though I can also help
or use Naruto
誰にでもチャクラを渡せる。
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA  NINJA
as an intermediary
to give my chakra to anyone...
ミナト…　てめえが　ナルトに→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA  NINJA  NINJA
The same exact way
you handed over
自分のチャクラを組み込んで→
NINE TAILS' CHAKRA
NARUTO
NINJA  NINJA  NINJA  NINJA
and inserted your own chakra
into Naruto, Minato.
渡していたやり方と同じだ。
こいつはもう…
とっくにてめえらを超えてるぜ。
He's already...
Surpassed you both
a while ago now.
リンクするチャクラ量も渡すチャクラ量も
規模が違う。
The amount of chakra
he's linking and delivering
is on a completely
different scale!
クシナ　ミナト…　ざまぁねえな
てめえら　ナルトのガキに負けてんぜ。
Kushina, Minato...
You're pathetic!
You both pale in comparison
to your brat Naruto!
フフフ…　まあ　これが…。
But this is probably...
（九喇嘛）貴様らが
ナルトにつなげたかった→
the power you wanted
to give to Naruto.
力なんだろうがな。
《マダラ：フッ…　俺ももう少し
力を貸してやるか》
Heh... I should probably lend
a little more power too.
《クソ！　力で押される…》
Damn it!
He's pushing me back hard!
ナルト　今のうちだ！　行け！
Naruto, now's your chance!
Do it now!
（キラービー）尾獣玉！
Tailed Beast Bomb!
《ミフネ：一閃！》
Beam of Light.
- Eight Trigrams Wall of Air Palm!
（みんな）八卦空壁掌！
（テマリたち）風遁　大掛け網！
- Wind Style: Giant Casting Net!
ネジの死は　無駄にはせん！
I won't let Neji's death
be in vain!
フンッ　一度かけてしまうと
死なねば消えぬ呪印。
A curse mark that doesn't
go away until you die...
日向の宗家と分家が生んできた
忍の呪い。
A shinobi curse that Hyuga's main
and branch families gave rise to...
かごの中で死を待つだけの存在。
An existence where one can
only await one's death inside a cage.
いい暗示だ　お前らは
さっき犬死にしたガキと同じだ。
It's a nice analogy for
our current situation.
You're all exactly like that brat
who just died a pointless death.
ネジの…。
Neji...
ネジの意志は…。
（みんな）うぉ～！
Neji's will...
まだ　死んじゃ…。
isn't...
いねえんだよ！
dead yet!
僕が右をやる！
I'll take the right!
よっしゃ！
Gotcha!
《クソ！　さっきので
肩がまた外れた》
Damn it! My shoulder's dislocated again!
（ヒナタ）柔拳！
Gentle Fist!
はっ！
いけ！　リー！
はい！
Go, Lee!
All right!
お前と違って　俺は…。
Unlike you guys, I don't want...
to sever any of my bonds...
or get them cut off!
つながってたもんを
切りたかねえし→
切られたくもねえんだよ。
ここか。
So this is it...
This place seems to be untouched.
（大蛇丸）
ここは　手つかずのようね。
It's in shambles.
（水月）ボロボロだね。
Well, I suppose it is way outside
the village.
（大蛇丸）そりゃ　こんな里の
はずれならね。
Which one is it?
どれだ？
さて　どこかに…。
Let's see, it should be
around here somewhere.
（大蛇丸）あったわ。
There it is.
なんか　気味が悪いね。
This place gives me the creeps...
見つけたんなら
さっさと行こうよ。
If we've found what
we were looking for,
let's get out of here!
そうね　行きましょう。
Yes, let's go...
すべての秘密が眠る場所へ。
to where all the secrets sleep.
Huh?
（水月）ん？
This place sure has changed a lot too.
ここも…　ずいぶん変わったな。
なんだ？　サスケのやつ。
What's up with Sasuke?
He's just like how I was before
I wanted to destroy Leaf.
私が　木ノ葉崩しをやる前と
同じね。
How so?
何が？
たとえ　彼や里が→
Even if both he and the village
have changed,
変わってしまったとしても→
this place is still his homeland.
ここは　彼の故郷に変わりない。
He needs some time to reaffirm
his decision and resolve,
（大蛇丸）感傷に浸り
過去をなぞることで→
through immersing himself in sentimentality
and by retracing the past.
己の決意を再確認する
時間が必要なのよ。
ふ～ん　なら　あんたは
もういいの？
Hmm...
So you're over it already?
（水月）感傷に浸りつつ
木ノ葉崩しの決意っての。
The whole immerse yourself
in sentimentality
to affirm your resolve
to destroy the Leaf thing.
Hey, come to think of it,
あのさ　よく考えたら
僕ら　あんたの部下で→
we were all your cream of
the crop subordinates, right?
トップメンバーだったでしょ。
And now...
we're inside of the Leaf...
んで今　それが木ノ葉の中にいる。
里のつわものどもは戦争でいない。
All the strong ones are gone
because they're away fighting.
Isn't this a perfect opportunity for you?
となると　これって
あんたにとってチャンスじゃないの？
フッ　そうかもね。
でもひとつ違ってるわ。
Perhaps, indeed...
Except for one thing...
You're no longer Hebi.
あなたたちは　もう蛇じゃない。
へぇ　術で開けんだ　入り口の石。
Oh, you use a jutsu to remove
the entry stone...
（大蛇丸）うちはの南賀ノ神社は
跡形もないのね。
There's not even a trace of
the Uchiha's Nakano Shrine...
うわべはいい。
大事なのはその下だ。　行くぞ。
The exterior doesn't matter.
What's important is what's beneath.
Let's go.
Well then, I'm going to get started.
なら始めるわよ。
少し離れてなさい。
It's best if you stand back.
グァ～。
((大蛇丸：巻物に
書かれてることをするには→
In order to perform
what is written in the scroll,
まず　死神の面が必要なのよ。
first, the Death God's Mask
is necessary.
それは木ノ葉のはずれ
うずまき一族の納面堂にある。
That is located in
the Uzumaki Clan's Noh Mask Hall
on the outskirts of the Leaf Village.
その面を使い屍鬼封尽の死神を
己に憑依させ　導き出す。
Then one must allow the Death God
of the Reaper Death Seal
to possess oneself and
guide it forth.
死神の腹を裂けば封印は解ける。
Slice open the Death God's abdomen
and the seal will come undone.
(ただ　私が
人柱になる必要はあるけどね))
Though I shall then end up
a human sacrifice.
グフッ！
However, it will also allow me
to get back
((大蛇丸：これで死神の中にあった
私の両手を→
both of my arms from inside
the Death God's belly.
(取り戻すことができる))
《戻ったわ》
They're mine again!
((大蛇丸：そうして私に
両手の力が戻れば→
And if I can regain the power
that lies in those arms,
I can perform the Reanimation.
穢土転生ができる。
そう　あの４人を…。
That's right...
I can revive those four.
もちろん　そうなれば
必要なものがいるの。
Of course in that case,
you're well aware of what will
then become necessary...
知ってるわね？
あ～　僕らを穢土転生の
いけにえにする気っすね！
You're planning on using us as sacrifices
for the Reanimation, aren't you?!
フフッ　それもいいけど→
That's not such a bad idea,
あんたなんかより
もっといいのがいるのよ。
but we've actually got something
even better than you guys.
(今は目に見えないけどね))
重吾　サスケ　水月　準備なさい。
（重吾）わかった。
((重吾　あなたがサスケに
呪印仙力を与えなさい))
((大蛇丸：そうすればトビがサスケの
監視役につけていたゼツが→
(そのチャクラに呼応して
表へ出てくるはず))
クソッ　なんで？
お前たち柱間細胞は→
実験で知り尽くしているのよ。
ハァ　ハァ…
もちろん　感知する方法もね。
やはり６体。　トビはずいぶん
慎重を期していたようね。
ぐうっ…。
((大蛇丸：
カブトからチャクラを吸い戻したとき→
彼の情報は私に蓄積された。
彼はちゃんとサスケにつけられていた
ゼツ６体を調べて知っていた。
私は４人の
個人情報物質を持っている。
(私も蓄積が好きでね))
水月　重吾
残りの２体を任せるわよ。
オーケーっすよ　大蛇丸様。
穢土転生の術！
（４人）うわぁ！
さあ　来るわよ！
すべてを知る者たち。
（大蛇丸）先代の火影たちが。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。